以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
所以我提到了随机线性
so I've mentioned randomized linear
代数几次，我觉得我很好
algebra a few times and I thought ok I'm
要跳进去描述随机的
gonna jump in and describe randomized
矩阵乘法它非常酷
matrix multiplication it's a pretty cool
这个想法在我看来是这样的
idea it seems to me so so this is a
随机线性代数中的主题
topic within randomized linear algebra
当我们会做任何这
and when would we be doing any of this
这将是对于那些刚刚矩阵
it would be for matrices that are just
真的很大，所以我们打算抽样
really really large so we plan to sample
a的列和样本
the columns of a and sample the
相应的B行实际上是
corresponding rows of B so actually the
当我们决定列时，我们也是
when we decide on a column we've also
决定连续，所以我们采取这些
decided on a row so we're taking those
正确加起来的B件
pieces which do correctly add up to a B
但我们不打算全部接受它们
but we're not going to take them all
我们要采取不同的人
we're going to take different ones
随机抽样我们的概率
randomly sampled with probabilities we
必须决定概率然后
have to decide probabilities and then
我们会加上我们的样品，我们希望
we'll add up our samples and we hope
结果接近于B的结果
that the result is close to a B that's
这个想法没关系，所以这个讲座呢
the idea okay so this this lecture then
所以我写了这些页面大约六个月
so I wrote these pages about six months
所以我一直在拼命想
ago so I've been desperately trying to
记得我写的是因为它不是
remember what I wrote because it's not a
以前我曾经说过的话题
subject I have ever spoken about before
但它是如此整洁，所以这里有一些
but it's so neat so here are some of the
事情进入它，我们必须
things that come into it we have to
决定我们想要的概率
decide on probabilities then we want to
计算均值所以它就是我们的
compute the mean so so it's it's our
有一些关键的第一天我
first day with some of these key I
从统计和概率，所以我们
from statistics and probability so we're
要采取增加一个的概率
gonna take probabilities that add to one
我们要弄明白是什么意思
we're gonna figure out what's the mean
我们希望和我们随机的B值
value of our random a B we hope and we
将看到的平均值
will see that the mean value of the
随机的B是正确的B但是那里
random a B is the correct a B but there
将是一个变化，我们不会得到每一个
will be a variance we won't get every
样品不会在事实上不正确
sample won't be correct in fact no
样品是正确的
samples will be correct
只有当我们平均添加它们时
only when we add them up on the average
我们得到纠正B的正确答案
the correct answer we get to correct a B
但所以意思是正确的
but so the mean will come out right
它会出来作为B你会看到它
it'll come out as a B you'll see it
发生
happen
是正确的，但不是很大的变化
correct but there's a big variance not
零将遍布整个地方
zero will be all over the place
我们的样品只是平均值
with our samples they'll just average
对了，但他们将全部结束
out right but they'll be all over
没有没有特别的样品将在权
no no particular sample will be right at
所以我们想要选择最好的
all so then we want to pick the best
这样我们工作的可能性
probabilities when the so our job will
一旦我们看到系统如何运作
be once we see how the system works
我们要分配概率和
we're going to assign probabilities and
我们要选择概率
we're going to choose the probabilities
最小化方差所以这是一个
that minimize the variance so this is a
典型情况下平均为
typical situation where the mean is
非常直截了当，做了什么
pretty straightforward and and does what
你想要但是有正确的意思
you want but having the correct mean
并不意味着你已经在取得了很好的答案
does not mean you've got good answers at
你知道的所有平均值都是负M
all the average of you know like minus M
零下一百一百是
minus a hundred and a hundred is it
可能是一个正确的答案是零但是
might be a correct answer is zero but
你离开了，这就是如何衡量的
you're way off so and this measures how
你是这样，我不知道你是否知道
far you are so I don't know if you know
这些话很不幸，但我想
these words it's unfortunate but I guess
1806五现在不能改变它了
1806 five can't change it now that the
差异写成Sigma平方和我们
variance is written Sigma squared and we
已经很好地使用了这封信
already have a good use for the letter
希腊字母Sigma但是
the Greek letter Sigma but
今天它有不同的用途
today it has a different use for
差异和这个拉格朗纳供应商将
variance and this lagron suppliers will
接近尾声所以基本上让我
come in near the end so basically let me
让我做一个实践例子来样
let me do a practice example to kind of
回想一下什么意思和方差以及什么
recall what mean and variance and what
那些是关于所以让我拿一个矩阵
those are about so let me take a matrix
通过2是1，所以我的我的矩阵只是
that's 1 by 2 so my my matrix is just
要做个B没关系我会说样品
gonna be a B okay I'm gonna sample that
两次和我的两个规则
and twice and my rule for the two
样品将是相同的，他们将
samples will be the same they will be
相同的完全分布式
identically distributed totally
相同，我的规则是什么
identical and what's my rule gonna be so
这就像我的做法规则是怎么回事
this is like practice my rule is going
是我拿那个专栏或那个专栏
to be I take that column or that column
概率1/2好吧，我做到了
with probabilities 1/2 okay and I do it
两次如此如此，我取平均值，从而
twice so so and I take the average so
我将采取他们的概率
I'm going to take probabilities they're
将是一个一半一半了
going to be one half one half for the
两列，我会做的等于
two columns and I'm gonna do s equal to
两个样本，我会增加重量
two samples and I'm gonna add weight
他们和我一起取平均值
them with and I'll take the average of
这两个样品还可以，这将是我的
the two samples okay and that will be my
随机矩阵好吧我们也可以
randomized matrix okay so could we
计算这个的意思所以我
compute the mean for this so I've
描述了随机抽样过程
described a randomized sampling process
我给你一半的概率
I've given you the probabilities half
我要去的次数是他的一半
and a half the number of times I'm going
做到这一点然后我除以那个
to do it and then I divide by that
所以我真的有这么多次
number of times so this is really I have
1在这儿是因为我有S的
a 1 over s here because I've got s of
这些现在这么哪些
these and now so what are the
这里的可能性我想找到
possibilities here I want to find the
首先意味着它
mean first of all it's
是一个卑鄙的好，所以这里有两个我可以
was a mean okay so here are two I could
想到两个不同的方法来计算
think of two different ways to compute
让我从这个开始的意思是什么
the mean let me start with this one what
是平均值均值的平均值
is the mean the average value mean means
第一样本的平均值，因此
average value of the first sample so the
第一个样本I的平均值
average value of the first sample I
将军的意思是什么？
would what does the mean the general
公式是你加起来所有的样本
formula is you add up all the sample
采样时间是可能的样本
sample times it's the possible samples
倍的概率，在这种
times their probabilities and in this
情况的概率是一半即
case the probabilities are one-half that
样本是零和一半
the sample is a zero and one half that
样本是零拍，所以那些是我的
the sample is zero beat so those are my
两个样本并计算平均值
two samples and computing the mean of
总得到哦，但这意味着
the total I get oh but that mean for
每个样本，但我必须繁殖
each sample but then I have to multiply
所以，让我把这里的一半放在这里
so so let's put what I got here half of
一个是为每一个样本的意义
a be that was the meaning of each sample
因为我的概率是相等的一半
because my probabilities were equal half
一半，现在我有两个人
and half and now I've got se for two
样本所以我乘以2得到一个B.
samples so I multiply by 2 and I get a B
并且平均值是正确的
and the mean mean is correct
好的，我们现在做的很简单
good we did the easy one the mean now
练习方差或退出
practice with the variance or else quit
在这里，也许我应该在我领先的时候退出
here maybe I should quit while I'm ahead
我的意思完全正确但是
I've got the mean exactly right but of
当然，样本可能不适合如此
course the samples might not be right so
对于方差现在怎么样呢？
what's so now for the variance so how do
什么是方差你还记得吗？
what is variance do you remember that
实际上有两种计算方法
there are actually two ways to compute
方差
variance
让我记住那里的人
let me just remember those over here and
把那块板推上去，以便方差Sigma
push that board up so the variance Sigma
如果你是的话，请原谅我
squared forgive me if you're a
统计学家就像你知道的那样
statistician this is like like you know
布伦特就像你出生时就知道这一点
Brent like you were born knowing this
但我们其他人不是这样的
but the rest of us were not so the
方差就是一种方法
variance is there's the sum one way to
这样做就是加起来的不同
do it is add up the different
不同事物的概率
probabilities of different things that
输出可能会减去平均值
could happen of output minus the mean
平方所以它一般它的
squared so it's the average it's the
平均距离肉的平方距离
average distance squared from the meat
所以它需要我的任何输出
so it takes whatever output I have that
输出数字减去平均值
came with output number I minus the mean
这是我平方的平均输出
which is the average output I square
那些和我得到一个数字，那种
those and I get a number and that sort
告诉我这是怎么告诉我的
of tells me how that tells me like in
在着名的高斯
the in the famous Gaussian
如果我在这里有高斯分布我
if I had a Gaussian distribution here I
分布为1/2和1/2
have a distribution of 1/2 and 1/2 so
我喜欢甚至可能有一个名字
I'm like that's maybe even has a name
像二项式或其他东西或伯努利
like binomial or something or Bernoulli
或者除了这个高斯之外的任何东西
or whatever but here on this Gaussian
我们都记得
that we all remember
我可以在那个图中标出什么
can I mark in the what in that figure
其中的意思是正确的
where the mean is that right in the
中心就像我，我可以，什么是
center like ok me and can and what is
方差只是为了回忆一下
the variance just to recall what
第一次大家都可以
everybody in the first time may even
听到那个词变异的是什么
hear that word variance the what is the
差异测量就是这样
variance kind of measuring it's it's
你的总和正方形，无论是
your you're summing squares so whether
你在平均值或权
you're on the right of the mean or the
左边的平均没有区别因为
left of the mean no difference because
你正在瞄准它，这是距离
you're squaring it and it's the distance
所以方差就是这样的意思
so so the mean the variance would be
有点像典型的宽度也许我
sort of like a typical width maybe I
过度了，但这将是一种
overdid it but that would be a sort of
典型的西格玛我真的只是因为
typical Sigma I'm really just since the
单词统计均值和方差
words statistics mean and variance
在1806年没有提到五个
haven't been mentioned in 1806 five
直到今天，我只是回忆起来
until today I'm just kind of recalling
他们还好，所以现在我准备计算了
them ok so now I'm prepared to compute
这个例子好吧也许我也许我会
this example ok maybe I'll maybe I'll
在这里计算它确定所以我计算
compute it over here ok so so I compute
然后是每个样本的方差
the variance for each sample and then
我会乘以2因为我有两个
I'll multiply by two because I have two
那些样品是什么样的呢？
samples so what are they so this is the
西格玛平方的样本显然我可以
Sigma squared sample obviously I could
写下所有的可能性是的
write down all the possibilities yeah
让我这样做了一个月，因此
let me just do this a month so the
样本可能已经选出0
sample could either have picked out a 0
或0B，概率为1/2
or 0 B and the probabilities were 1/2 so
II的概率次数是概率的1/2倍
I I have 1/2 times the probability times
输出让我们说输出是
the output let's say the output is
零减去已结束的平均值
a zero minus the mean which was a over
超过两个，我想把它解决
to be over two and I want to square that
所以这是我的一种可能性
so that was one possibility when I
选了零，另一个选了
picked a zero and the other one which
我也在做概率1/2
I'm also doing with probability 1/2 is
如果我选择0B你看到了什么
in case I picked 0 B what was you see
因为差异，我不是0
I'm I'm not getting 0 for the variance
因为每次我都犯了错误
because every time I'm making an error
每次我都没有得到正确的答案
every time I'm never getting the correct
一个零或正确的零B，因为我
a zero or the correct zero B because I'm
总是在中间做这个好吗
always doing this one in the middle okay
现在，如果我计算所有我得到的
now if I compute all that I get a
量，也许我只是要上
quantity and maybe I'll just be to be on
安全的一面
the safe side
如果我写的，请问你的原谅
ask your forgiveness if I write the
回答，我们甚至可以尝试得到
answer and we could even try to get the
回答，但这是两个样本
answer but so this is from two samples
所以这是翻了一番一个做
so this is doubled that one do
我想我足够大胆尝试如此
I guess I'm bold enough to try it so so
零，所以这将是一个减去
a zero so that would be a minus a over
我认为两个和一个B和一个B超过两个
two and a B and a B over two I think
我认为看起来有一半了
we've got here one half of I think looks
对我来说就像一个超过两平方加B
to me like a over two squared plus B
我失去了正负，但它
over I'm missing by plus or minus but it
当我把它们整理成一体时
when I'm squaring them that's the whole
方差点没关系和
point of variance doesn't matter and the
B超过两个，在这里我想我就是我
B over two and here I think I'm I'm
两个人错了，我错了
wrong by a over two and I'm wrong by
加上B超过
plus by B over
两个或八个超过两个，但当我
two or minus eight over two but when I
把它们放在一起并不重要，所以我
square them again doesn't matter so I
我认为我得到了另外两半
think I get another half of a over two
正方形加B超过2平方
squares plus B over 2 squared
原谅我这么简单
what forgive me for this simple
计算，但只是为了练习那么
computation but just to practice so what
如果我得到了一半的话
have I got I've got a half of that in
的一半，这样加起来是这个
half of that so that adds up to this
平方超过四加B平方的东西
thing a squared over four plus B squared
超过四，但我正在做两个样本
over four but then I'm doing two samples
我会通过数量乘以
I'll have to multiply by the number of
样本所以我想两次两次
samples so I think so times two for two
我认为我得到的样本是1/4
samples I think I'm getting it was 1/4
但现在它将是平方B的1/2
but now it'll be 1/2 of a squared B
广场哦是的我没有呀呀嘿
Square oh yeah I didn't yeah yeah hey
是的，我认为我认为这是正确的
yeah I think I think that's right but
原谅我，我只是问自己是的
forgive me while I just ask myself yeah
是的，这实际上已经是你了
yeah this will be actually you already
有这些笔记
have these notes
这是第2.4节，所以我认为它是
this is section 2.4 so it's I think it's
他们自己的stiller所以有什么意义
their own stiller so what's the point of
这第一点是要记住
this first point was to like remember
进入的一些步骤
some of the steps that go into the
方差哦还有另一个公式
variance oh there's another formula for
我要告诉你和你的差异
variance that I want to tell you and the
第二点是要在把
second point is to make to bring in a
新想法假设我们想要做到这一点
new idea suppose we want to make this
假设这种差异比我们大
suppose this variance is bigger than we
我想假设B很多
want suppose for example that B is a lot
不是假设b越大很多大
bigger than a suppose B is a lot bigger
比那应该我们做
than a then what should we have done
不同的随机随机
differently in this random randomized
线性代数，如果我想要得到这个
linear algebra if I'm trying to get this
事关亲近那个东西和
thing closed get close to that thing and
如果B比那么大了
if B is a lot bigger than a then what
我应该做些不同的事
should I do different
我不知道B究竟是什么，但我
I don't know what B is exactly but I
拥有更大的信息
have the information that it's bigger
比那时我应该增加了
than a then I should increase the
概率我不应该做一半
probability I shouldn't do half and half
所以这里是随机抽样
so here here was randomized sampling
取平均值我的概率是
taking the average my probabilities were
一半，但如果我想要我
a half and a half but if I want I
相信我可以保持平均值
believe that I could keep the mean
当然这是正确的
correct of course that's fundamental to
得到正确的权利，并获得更好的
get the mean right and get a better
答案比这更小
answer get a smaller variance than that
B通过挑选那个方形在那里
B squared over there by picking that
那个概率更高的东西
thing with higher probability so that's
随机的'男人出去的地方
where the randomized 'men out to be
称为norm平方概率I
called norm squared probability the I
什么是概率的决定
the the decision on what the probability
应该是事实证明是
should be goes it turns out to be the
最优的一个与广场相符
optimal one goes with the square of the
如果B是a和I的两倍那么大小
size so if B is twice as big as a and I
想要得到方差然后
want to get the variance down then the
概率我应该使用概率
probability I should use probabilities
这是经常的四倍四倍
that are four times four times as often
我会选择B而不是那个
I will choose B than a that's going to
是两点钟的结论
be the conclusion at two o'clock
希望没关系，所以这是一点
hopefully okay there so that's one point
并且，只是另一个小点，同时
and and just another little point while
我们正在审查方差
we're while we are reviewing variance
这是对标准公式
this is the standard formula for the
所有可能的方差和
variance sum of all the possible
结果与他们的概率
outcomes with their probabilities the
距离均方的距离是多少？
distance from the mean squared do you
知道第二公式，这是非常
know a second formula which is very
接近这个和它非常相似
close to this and very similar and it
来自于取代的含义
comes from substituting the meaning of
意味着平均值是这样的东西
means something where the mean is so
是啊，所以我只是我只是想提
yeah so I just I just want to mention a
第二个公式，我不知道
second formula and I don't I don't know
哪一个实际上会使用但是
which one will actually use but the
相同数量的第二个公式
second formula for the same quantity
西格玛广场是这个总和
Sigma square is this sum of
概率乘以输出平方所以我
probabilities times output square so I
没有减去这个中的平均值
haven't subtracted off the mean in this
第二个公式我现在必须这样做
second formula I have to do it now and
我会做的意思是我会做所有的意思
I'll do the mean I'll do the mean all at
一旦均方当然的意思
once mean squared of course the mean
涉及记住，平均是
involves remember that the mean is the
概率乘以的概率
sums of the probabilities times the
结果，它只是玩一个
outcomes and it's just playing with a
小代数表明你可以
little algebra to show that you can
或者你可以选择任何东西
either you have a choice of whatever is
更方便的是减去平均值
more convenient subtract the mean off
从每个输出或做所有输出
from each output or do all the outputs
但是你没有考虑到
but then you haven't accounted for the
事实上，你真的想要距离
fact that you really want the distances
从平均值然后你减去
from the mean and then you subtract off
平均值有两种方法可以做到
the mean squared two ways to do it
有两种方法可以做到这一点，是的，我们
two ways to equal ways to do it yeah we
将审查平均和。的基本思想
will review the basic ideas of mean and
在该部分中的差异
variance in the in the in the section on
这里的概率我是的问题是的
probability here I'm yes question yeah
这里的意思是哦
the mean oh in in here
在分开是的，这是重点
at separate yeah that's the whole point
是啊所以这是喜欢做这个，然后
yeah so this was like do this and then
减去均方或保持
subtract off the mean squared or keep
在每个学期的平均值，并做到这一点
the mean in every term and do it that
办法
way
你可以验证这两个是
you could verify that the two are are
同样没关系所以当我们现在去的时候
the same okay so when we go now to the
更大的问题我忘了哪个方向
bigger question I've forgotten which way
我这样做但是我可以自由选择好吧
I do it but I'm free to choose okay is
就像一个小样本合理而且
that like a small sample reasonable and
你和你明白如果我们
you and you get the idea that if if we
知道如果我们看看我们的矩阵
know that if we if we look at our matrix
首先，找出哪些列
first of all and find out which columns
是大点大规范和哪个
are large dot large norm and which
列小则可能是
columns are smaller then that might be
有用的信息来衡量我们的
useful information to weight our
挑选较大的概率
probabilities to pick the larger one
更经常没关系，其实让我好吧
more often okay okay well in fact let me
告诉你这两者是什么
just tell you what are the two
可能还有一个就是我刚才
possibilities there one is what I just
说等你的概率
said wait your probabilities by the
这个规范平方的常数平方
square of the norm this norm squared
等待，我们会看到并采取
waiting that we'll see and take the
列虽然来了，但更高
columns as they come but with higher
大栏目或你的概率
probability on the big columns or you
可以说另一种方式是混合
could say another way would be mix the
列使它们或多或少都有
columns so that they more or less have
相似的尺寸，然后跟踪
similar sizes and then keep track of
你做了什么，然后然后
what you've done and then and then just
概率都可以相等，
the probabilities can all be equal so
这将是你的另一种方式
that would be the other way take your
矩阵混合起来采取组合
matrix mix it up take combinations of
用随机数列有
the columns with random numbers there's
一个随机的世界在这里带你做一个混合
a random world here take you do a mixing
然后对混合矩阵进行操作
and then operate on the mixed matrix
是啊好吧，我打算这样做第一
yeah okay I'm going to do it the first
方式我会选择这些概率
way I'm gonna pick these probabilities
他们将会变成现实
to there'll be they'll turn out to be
与正常平方成正比准备好了
proportional to norm squared okay ready
为此它来了
for that here it comes
所以把它带下来是的，好吧我
so bring that down yeah okay actually I
它告诉我们，现在可以把它留下来
could leave it up for now cuz it told us
我们正在做什么
what we're what we're up to
好吧所以我得到了什么
okay so so what have I got
让我看看我是否可以这样，所以我们
let me just see if I can so so we're
乘以B次，我们会
multiplying a times B and we're gonna
使用PJ的这些概率
use these probabilities PJ is going to
是该列的长度乘以
be the length of that column times the
那排长度的平方很好
length of that row norm squared well
如果我将a乘以a，则规范平方
norm squared if I was multiplying a by a
转置然后我真的会
transpose then I really would be
平方那将是相同的
squaring that would be the same as that
所以我要使用norm平方这个词
so I'm gonna use the word norm squared
或长度平方也在这里
or length squared also here where the
我不假设B是一个
two I'm not assuming that B is a
转置没关系
transpose okay
这将是概率意志
so that will be the probabilities will
与此成正比，但现在是那些
be proportional to that but now those
那个不加一个，所以我该怎么做
that don't add up to one so how do I
使概率加起来一个
make the probabilities add up to one
这是选择的概率
this is the probability of of choosing
斧子列J排J是什么的
column J of a x times row J that's what
这就是PJ所说的好
that's what PJ refers to okay
好吧那我的计划是什么哦我必须这样做
okay so what is my plan oh I have to
使概率加到一个或我
make the probabilities add to one or I'm
真的打破了他们的基本法
really breaking them the fundamental law
在这里，如果我有一堆
here so how if I have a bunch of
概率，我有点知道我
probabilities and I kind of know what I
想要，但他们没有加起来一个
want but they don't add up to one what
我做他/他们的总和让我打电话看
do i do / their sum let me call see
有一些所以概率正在发生
there's some so the probability is going
是C和C的目标
to be that over C and C is is going to
是许多行和的总和
be the sum of however many rows and
列我想也许我有R和我的
columns I guess maybe I had R and my
一个JVJ转换的图片好吧所以
picture of a J VJ transpose okay so all
我做的是重新调整概率
I did was rescale the probabilities so
他们现在添加到一个好的，所以
that they now add to one good okay so
现在我准备去上班了，我已经准备好了
now I'm ready to go to work I'm ready to
选择哦是的所以这是我的规则
choose oh yes so here's my rule I will
选择行列和列行J
choose row column and column row J with
这个概率但是我要去
this probability but then I'm going to
乘以它，如果我，我可以自由地做到这一点
multiply it and I'm free to do that if I
我希望如此近似我的
want to so my approximation my
近似ami将是我会接受这个
approximate ami will be I'll take this
无论哪个出来我都会把AJ当成
whichever comes out I'll take the AJ be
j转置出来它出来了
j transpose there comes out it comes out
有概率PJ，但我要去
with probability P J but I'm going to
除以此，我想我就是这样
divide this by and I think I'm this is
正确的样本数量
the right one s the number of samples
PJ所以我一开始就想到了
times PJ so I thought at first that's
奇怪的
weird
去了所有的麻烦来接这些P
went to all the trouble to pick these P
J声称这些都是好事
J's claiming that these are the good
所以我是我最终证明的主张
ones so I'm my claim to eventually prove
最后我首先要明白
at the end first I'll have to understand
采样是如何做到这一点就像
how the sampling is done that's like the
最重要的但是当我走的时候
most important but then when I go
计算平均值我会得到正确的
to compute the mean I'll get the correct
意思是当我去计算时
mean and when I go to get to compute the
方差我会为一些表达
variance I'll get some expression for
方差然后计划将是
the variance and then the plan will be
选择这些PJ来减少总数
choose these PJ's to minimize that total
方差所以这就是这个
variance so here so this is what that's
一个这是一个典型的样本
a that's a typical sample with
概率PJ挑选那个矩阵
probability PJ pick that that matrix
秩一个矩阵，那么我的
that rank one matrix so then my
近似值B是所有这些的总和
approximate a B is the sum of all these
超过你的样品你和我一起让我
over s samples are you with me let me
让我重复一遍，我正在努力
let me just repeat I'm trying to
乘以B每个样本只是一个
multiply a B each sample is just a
单列时间排，所以它的方式
single column times row so it's way
错误的方式错了它只是一小块
wrong way wrong it's just a tiny piece
一个B，但我拿了那个样本
of a B but I take that sample with
概率PJ和我用sPJ把它
probability PJ and I divide it by s PJ
所以这是PJ的取消哦哦，好的
so that's a PJ's cancel here oh yes okay
对，所以我想看看
right so I would like to see that the
意思是正确的我想看到
mean is correct I would like to see that
平均值是正确的我要计算
the mean is correct I'm going to compute
我的过程的意思是它就像它
the mean of my process so it's like it's
落到我的腿上，我做到了
falling into my lap here I made it that
办法
way
这些PJ取消了我除以s
these PJ's canceled I divided by s so
典型样本的平均值将是如此
the mean of a typical sample will be so
一个样本的平均值是
the mean of one sample is the
得到它的概率是我的
probability of getting it times what I
这样它只是jbj的总和
take so it's just the sum of a jb j
transpose/s你会说好的
transpose / s you're going to say okay
你在浪费我们的时间，但我们有一个
you're wasting our time but we've got a
我只是想证明我是
I would just want to show that I'm
得到正确的意思
getting the correct mean
出于这个计划，所以你看到了
out of this plan so do you see that if
这是一个样本的平均值所以是什么
that's a mean of one sample so what's
所有样本总和的平均值
the mean of the sum of all the samples
好吧x是的，因为它是相同的意思
well x yes because it was the same mean
每个样本都是同样的意思
every sample that the same mean just
就像我们的小联盟一样
just as it did in our little league
练习的例子就是这样的意思
practice example so that's the mean of
一个样本，所以所有样本的平均值
one sample so the mean of all samples
添加加在一起乘以此
added added together multiplies this by
是的取消了，我得到了B记住
s yeses cancel and I get a B remembering
我的方式是，我在那里定义了B，是的
my however way I defined a B there yeah
我在这里说的就是我做的
all I'm saying there here is that I did
抽样中合理的东西
something reasonable in the sampling
过程让平均出来了
process so that the mean came out right
现在是困难的部分
and now is the hard part
差异什么是方差好吧
the variance what's the variance okay so
我有什么需要计算的，我可以
what do I have to compute and I may it
将取决于P1至PRI
will depend on the piece P 1 to P R I
我猜我们有不同的行
guess we had we had our different rows
不同的列行对可供选择和
different column row pairs to choose and
我们选择了这些家伙的概率
we chose probabilities these guys that
取决于大小，现在我要去
depended on the size and now I'm going
计算方差，它不会
to compute the variance and it won't be
0因为每个样本都是错的我是
0 because every sample is wrong I'm
从来没有从样本中得到样本
never getting from a sample a sample is
只是给我写了一篇专栏文章
just giving me a wrote a column times a
排名第一的人
row a rank one guy
他们平均给出了
and they averaged out to give the
正确的产品但每一个都是
correct product but each one is
肯定是错的，因为它只是一个等级
certainly wrong because it's just a rank
一，所以当我计算方差时，我会去
one so when I compute variance I'm going
肯定不会在零中得到零
to definitely not get zero right in
其他的话当然是什么时候的
other words of course when were the
如果B排名，则方差为零
variance be zero yeah if a B were ranked
一个我想每一次我会得到它的权利
one I guess I'd get it right every time
谢谢哦，有一个比我更好的答案
thanks oh there's a better answer than I
记住，是的，差异会
had in mind yeah yeah the variance would
如果每个样本都是正确的，则只有零
only be zero if every sample was right
如果等级是这样的话，那就是真的
and that would be true if the rank was
一个，只有一件事
one and there was only one thing to
选择，但这不是我们的问题
choose but that's not the problem we
想要好，所以差异就在我的心里
want okay so the variance is there my my
本能是告诉你这是什么
instinct is to tell you what this
计算产生，因为你和我可以
calculation produces since you and I can
读，你会允许我这样做吗
read would you allow me to do that so
结果是样本的方差
here the variance for a sample turns out
事实证明我们会这样做
to be it turns out to equal so we will
想办法
figure it out
结果等于它的总和
turns out to equal the sum over as it
是AJAJ转置的
was up there of the AJ AJ transpose
可能是平方让我只是检查
probably squared let me just just check
是的，是的，为什么我不帮助自己
yes squared yeah why don't I help myself
这是因为这些是平方的
here so these are squared because
方差是平方然后当我
variances are squared and then when I
看看我认为有什么是S
look to see what I think there's an S
那里有一个PJ，为什么有一个
there and there's a PJ so why is there a
PJ那里取消了，所以在这里
PJ there when it cancelled here so here
当我乘以那个PJ时
the PJ when I multiplied by that
取消为什么不取消
cancelled why doesn't it cancel over
因为它在那边平方
there because it's squared over there
那边的东西是平方所以它
over there this thing is squared so it
那是PJ两次
was PJ twice here
PJ是概率一次，所以我仍然是我们
PJ it's probability once so I'm still we
得到PJ的分母1因子
got the PJ in the denominator 1 factor
PJ在分母中然后如此
of PJ in the denominator and then so
那就是我猜我正在做的就是我
that is I guess what I'm doing is I'm
以这种方式计算方差就是这样
computing the variance this way so what
我的电脑现在是他的第一位
I've computer now is his first bit and
然后我说应该减去
then I said should should subtract the
平均值，这是一个样本
mean squared and this is for one sample
所以平均值是我认为它转
so the mean squared is I think it turns
出为1以上s乘以C倍一个乙
out to be 1 over s times C times a B
在这个弗罗贝尼乌斯规范中，这就是它的平方
squared in this Frobenius norm it's it's
一个平方加B平方的东西
the a squared plus B squared stuff that
我以前见过这么好，所以我跳了
I saw before so okay so this I've jumped
从总和中获得一个重要的一步
a serious step to get from the sum
插入的方差的公式
formula for the variance I've plugged in
这个问题，现在好了
this problem and got that okay and now
我要抽样让我们看看它在哪里
I'm gonna sample let's see where it yeah
哦，我想要简化这个
oh I want I would like to simplify this
我想简化一下，所以我有
I would like to simplify that so I have
插上PJ好吧所以我必须这样做
to plug in the PJs okay so I have to
插入那个PJ，我们决定了什么
plug in for that PJ and we decided what
PJ将会是
PJ was going to be
这里好了，所以当我插入的是在
here okay so when I plug that in in the
分母将取消其中一个
denominator it will cancel one of these
我只需要一个JPG的总和
and I'll just have a sum of a JPG of a
JPjbj规范和C是什么
JP j bj norms and what's that is C so
让我再说一遍吧
let me say this again just it's
你什么时候可以检查一下
something you can just check when you
插入那个值时有一分钟
have a minute when I plug in that value
对于PJ，它取消了正方形和
for PJ here it cancels the squares and
只留下第一个力量所以我就是
just leaves the first power so then I'm
加起来的第一个力量，我得到了C.
adding up the first power and I get C
但是PJ中有一个因子C.
and but the PJ had a factor C in the
分母，它在分母中
denominator and it's in the denominator
那边是C，所以它就在那里
over there so that C is up there so it's
C平方来到这里一个恒定的方格
C squared coming here a constant square
减去另一个词有1个超过s
minus the other term there's a 1 over s
这最终会消失，这
that will eventually go away and this
其他任期是1比s更多也许是
other term is 1 over s more maybe the
弗罗贝尼乌斯的规范很好，也许一个
Frobenius norm squared well maybe one
在SS上，所以你看到了我
over SS are so you're seeing and I
道歉
apologize
代数一点点凌乱位
a little bit messy bit of algebra a
有点凌乱的代数但是
little bit messy bit of algebra but
这就是我们最终的结果
that's what we that's what we ended up
当我们采取样品和时
with and when we take s samples and
结合它们将取消s和
combine them that will cancel the s and
我认为，当我们这样做时，它会敲出来
the I think it'll knock that out when we
结合s样品好吧好的
combine the s samples okay yeah okay
知道现在我们可以选择那些
know what now we get to choose those
概率以及我们将如何进行
probabilities and how are we gonna
选择他们什么是最好的选择
choose them what will be the best choice
这是方差的表达式
here's the expression for the variance
是的，这很好，这很好
yeah this is good this is good
从现在开始和你在一起，依靠你
stay with me from now on you you you
你会对自己说的
you'll be saying to yourself there's
那里的一些步骤，我没有完全看到
some steps there that I didn't see fully
我想检查但是我同意但是
and I want to check but and I agree but
让我说我们达到了这一点
let me say that we get to that point and
这是一个固定的数字，所以它是我们的C.
this is a fixed number so it's C that we
我想做小，这就是我们的
would like to make small and that's our
最后的工作这对任何选择都是如此
final job this was true for any choice
P的概率哦，是的，是的
of the probabilities P well oh yeah yep
是的，所以我想这仍然有
yep so I want to the this still had in
可能性是啊我在哪里
it the probabilities yeah where do I
我想要表明那些
want to do I want to show that those
这是最好的选择，这是
that was the best choice that this was
最好的选择，是的，我想表明这一点
the best choice yeah I want to show that
这是最佳选择
that's the best choice that's a choice
基于概率的概率权重
of weights of probabilities based on the
一段时间的长度是B的长度
length of a time's the length of B of
当然听起来不合理
course that sounds reasonable doesn't it
我们想要四个大的大柱子和大的
we want to four big big columns and big
我们想要更高的行
rows we want to have a higher
选择那些的概率，但是
probability to choose those but is the
概率与长度成正比
probability proportional to the length
两者都应该成比例
of both or should it be proportional to
10次​​幂或平方根或
the 10th power or the square root or
那是我们最后一步的结果
what that's what our final step of
优化P所以这是最后的
optimizing the P so this is the final
步
step
优化概率P1到PsI.
optimize the probabilities P 1 to P s I
猜测没有P1到PR的R行或
guess no P 1 to P R for the R rows or
a和我们的B行主题的列
columns of a and our rows of B subject
他们必须加起来为1，
to their you have to add up to 1 and
我的意思是优化是什么意思
what do I mean by optimize I mean
最小化这是优化手段
minimize this is optimize means
最小化这个表达C所以AJBJ
minimizing this expression C so AJ BJ
转移到哪里是PG的希望
transfer where's it's the over PG o hope
帮忙
help help
所以让我看到亚我已经方差
so let me just see ya my variance has
得到一个PJ是的，我的差异对不起我
got a PJ in it yeah my variance sorry my
方差哦，这是我的差异
variance oh okay this is my variance
如果我做对了，这就是结果
this is the result if I make the right
对，如果我做出这个选择的选择
choice for the if I make this choice for
概率，但我正在备份一个
the probabilities but I'm backing up a
分钟，这是，如果这是与
minute this is if this is the with
最佳
optimal
PJ然后我们得到了那么好的回答
PJ's then we got that answer great that
是我们的答案
was our answer
但我正在支持这个并说
but I'm backing up to this and saying
什么是最佳PJs
what are the optimal PJs for to make
这种差异很小，所以我才是真的
this variance small so I'm I'm really
我只是做着这样做，我让我
I'm just doing what doing this I let me
就在那里，问题更简单，最小化
right there the problem simpler minimize
一些豌豆等于一些
with the some of the peas equal one some
数量q平方超过QJ/PJ是的
quantity q squared over QJ / PJ yeah
那就是你怎么这些qJS那个
that's it how do you so these q JS that
我刚刚介绍了那封信
i just introduced that letter for are
AJBJ他们可能是他们的
the AJ B J's they're they're given maybe
我只是把AJPJ放回去了
I'll just put put back AJ PJ so to
重复这是计算
repeat this is the calculation of the
方差睡衣的任何选择，这是
variance for any choice of PJs this is
如果我做出最好的选择，我会得到什么
what I get if I make the best choice but
在这里我要告诉它是
over here I'm gonna show that it is the
最好的选择因为它是选择
best choice because that it's the choice
这使得这个结果小到了
that makes this result as small as
可能这就是Mulder的呻吟声
possible so that's the the groans Mulder
钳子方面所以我们有统计数据
plier aspect so we there statistics has
已经完成我得到了我得到这个
been done I'm get I'm getting this
回答而不是放入一些
answer and instead of putting in some
奇怪的Q让我把在这些是什么
weird Q let me put in what these are
他们不管他们是一群
they're whatever they're bunch of
数字，但我除以PJ和
numbers but I'm dividing by the PJ and
你怎么找到最好的PJ你知道吗？
how do you find the best PJ do you know
关于那个优化问题我他们
about that optimization question I they
必须添加到一个和Grouch有
have to add to one and the Grouch had
伟大的想法，所以这可能是
the great idea so this is maybe the
我们第一次使用他的想法，所以你
first time we've used his idea so do you
记得他的想法
remember what his idea
他接受了这个约束并且建立了
he takes this constraint and he builds
它成为他乘以它的函数
it into the function he multiplies it by
一些不为人知的神秘数字
some unknown mysterious number often
叫做lambda但与此毫无关系
called lambda but nothing to do with
的关注的特征值
eigenvalues of the concern of the
PI应该添加的约束
constraints that the PI's should add to
一个，所以他零，他有零，但有
one so he had zero he had zero but with
一个变量lambda，这是拉格朗日的
a variable lambda this is Lagrange's
想法所以这是它很整洁，这
idea so it's it's pretty neat that this
问题我离开了随机抽样
problem I've left randomized sampling
我到达了这个最后的子问题
I've arrived at this final subproblem
优化下的概率
optimizing the probabilities under the
条件，他们添加到一个和
condition that they add to one and
拉格朗日的想法是建立这个等式
Lagrange's idea was build that equation
进入功能然后你可以采取
into the function then you can take
衍生品，但你也采取
derivatives but you also take
关于λ的衍生物
derivatives with respect to lambda
因为现在这是一个未知的你和你
because that's now an unknown and you
解决你将导数设置为零
solve you set the derivatives to zero
你会得到答案就像一个
and you get the answer it's like a
奇迹，但如果你已经看到了地面
miracle but if you've seen the ground
这是一个令人困惑的奇迹就是它
it's a confusing miracle that's what it
是啊好吧，如果我走了
is yeah okay so if I take the
豌豆规格的衍生物
derivatives of the spec to the peas set
他们为零我认为我会得到
them to zero I think I'm going to get
推荐的豆豆让我这么做
the recommended Peas so that so I've
我用a计算了最终的答案
I've computed the final answer with a
推荐作品，但现在我要
recommended piece but now I'm going to
表明他们确实是这样推荐的
show that they really are recommended so
你可以采取的衍生
can you take the derivative of that with
尊重P，我可以提出这个问题
respect to P could I just raise this a
很少提高它好一点
little raise it a little more okay take
关于每个P的P的导数
the derivative with respect to P each P
因为我有未知数
because I've got n unknowns there are
然而，许多人可能都是未知数而且我已经知道了
however many maybe are unknowns and I've
得到lambda所以我有R加1件事
got lambda so I've got R plus 1 things
那么这个突破到P的衍生物是什么
so what's the derivative this break to P
行演算采取衍生物即
okay calculus take the derivative that
这是一个JVJ转换为减号
it's a J VJ transpose over with a minus
PJ正确
P J squared right
以及相关的衍生物
and the derivative of that with respect
到PJ是负lambda所以那是
to PJ is minus lambda so that's
衍生出幽灵PJ是0和
derivative the specter PJ is 0 and the
导数，所以这是衍生物
derivative so this was the derivative
关于PJ必须是0然后
with respect to PJ has to be 0 and then
对lambda的衍生方面
the derivative respect to lambda into
尊重lambda就是JSJS减去
respect to lambda is that JS JS minus
等于1lagravis混淆了整体
equals 1 the lagravis confused the whole
世界，但他给了我们一个休息时间
world but he gave us a break that in the
只是衍生出幽灵lambda
derivative the specter lambda it just
因为他带回了约束
brings back the constraint because he
刚用lambda因子构建它
just built it in with a factor lambda
然后他拿出了衍生物而且它
then he took the derivative and it
带回了约束但是这个
brought back the constraint but this
部分是美丽的部分，我现在做什么
part is the beautiful part now what do I
从中吸取教训，有时甚至有时
learn from that and sometimes sometimes
这将是一个加号，为什么我不这样做
this would be a plus why don't I make it
只是为了让我的生活更轻松
a plus just to make my life easier
勒布朗说现在已经死了，他没有
LeBron said it's dead now and he don't
无论如何都要关心它是否接近-好吧
care anyway whether it's closer on - ok
好的，所以这就是告诉我这个
ok so so this is telling me this so this
告诉我什么什么击中倍增
is telling me what what hits multiplier
是他告诉我，如果这个等式
is he's telling me that if this equation
告诉我乘数是AJ
is telling me that the multiplier is AJ
VJ转置/PJ平方或放另一个
VJ transpose / PJ squared or put another
他告诉我PJ平方的方式就是我
way he's telling me that PJ squared is I
猜猜我希望漂亮之后
guess I'm hoping that after the pretty
我们采取的令人困惑的步骤是一个
confusing steps that we took this is a
用数学的单独一点点
separate a little bit of math using the
LaGrant适用或想法，我希望如此
LaGrant apply or an idea and I hope that
你的想法将是你的结果
your your result your thought will be
男孩很简单，所以我要去
boy that was pretty simple so I'm gonna
把PJ平方是这里的车道
put the PJ Squared's here in the lane
好吧，这告诉我什么看
okay well what does this tell me look
我已经采取了衍生规范来
I've taken the derivative the spec to
PJ和我得到了每个的等式
the PJs and I got this equation for each
J但是我把导数部分拿走了
J but I took the derivative the partial
衍生物回到每个睡衣和
derivatives back to each of the PJs and
它告诉我PJ平了等一下
it tells me that PJ squared wait a
分钟什么是广场因此
minute what's the square and therefore
帮助我只有两分钟哦
help I've only got two minutes and oh
他们必须加一个哦是的lambdas
they have to add to one oh yeah lambdas
要救我们哈哈吧
gonna save us haha right
拉姆达是想救我们，因为
lambda is gonna save us because the
总概率所以PJ将是
total probabilities so PJ will be the
这个东西的平方根然后我
square root of this stuff and then I the
号码lambda我还没有决定
number lambda I haven't decided
拉格朗日乘数还没有决定这样
Lagrange's multiplier haven't decided so
它是什么才是正确的数字
what is it it's the correct number to
使这等于一，所以就是这样
make this equal to one so that's that is
C哦天哪，我得到了平方根
the C oh god what have I got square root
我应该开始拍摄
there shoot I should have started with
方块所以这些应该是正方形啊
squares so these should be squares ah
谢谢
thank you
你可以告诉我早些时候使用的时候
you could have told me earlier use when
你看到有麻烦的教授没有
you see a professor in trouble don't
让我只是让他挂在那儿好吧
let's just let him hang there okay right
好吧，这是AJBJ所以除了
okay and this is AJ BJ so apart from the
kerfuffle在这里和笔记得到它
kerfuffle here and the notes get it
是的，因为我有时间在那里思考
right because I had time to think there
结果证明这一点
that it it turns out that
这个最优给出了公式
this optimum gave the formula for the
PJS我以前使用，所以当我
PJs that I used earlier so when I
介绍这个公式，我说让我们
introduced this formula I said let's
让我们选择那些概率
take let's choose those probabilities
但后来我回到了最后
but then I came back at the very end and
表明他们是概率
showed that they are the probabilities
这样可以最大限度地减少方差
that minimize the variance so that's
就像今天的讲座你能想到的那样
like today's lecture can you just think
一分钟，但请回去
a minute but please do go back through
笔记因为有些杂乱
the notes because there's some messy
我在那里的差异步骤
steps in the variance there that I had
快点过去，但你明白了
to go by quickly but you understand the
我们建立一个随机的原则
principle that we set up a randomized
系统我们选择概率瞄准
system we we choose probabilities aiming
获得最小的最好的
to get the the best the smallest
差异，事实证明，好
variance and it turns out that the good
列时的概率更大
probabilities are bigger when the column
是一个更大的列，以便使用
is a big a larger column so that to use
这你必须通过矩阵
this you have to go through the matrix
并找到列的长度
and find the lengths of the columns
因为那是告诉你的
because that's what's telling you the
概率所以这就像第一个
probabilities so that's a like a first
在你做之前通过
pass through before you do the
随机抽样你必须决定
randomized sampling you must decide on
概率和它们取决于
the probabilities and they depend on the
不同栏目的大小谢谢
sizes of the different columns thank you
让我通过，我会来
for getting me through that I'll come
回多一点关于随机
back to a little more about randomized
事情下次再往后不多
things next time and then later not much
但后来一点点后，我们会
later but a little bit later we'll be
seeing probability much more seriously
更加认真地看待概率
好的谢谢你
okay thank you